<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sceckert.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://sceckert.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-09-19T22:47:05-04:00</updated><id>https://sceckert.github.io/</id><title>Sierra Eckert</title><author><name>Sierra Eckert</name><email>sierra.c.eckert@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title>The Type-Writer Girl,</title><link href="https://sceckert.github.io/major-list/allen-typewriter-girl-notes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Type-Writer Girl," /><published>2016-04-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-04-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://sceckert.github.io/major-list/allen-typewriter-girl-notes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sceckert.github.io/major-list/allen-typewriter-girl-notes/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;general-notes&quot;&gt;General Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Genre-bending and and Gender-bending
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Framing: The Odsessy written by a  woman&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Novella that aspires to be “epic of imagination” (a modern &lt;em&gt;Odyssey&lt;/em&gt;),  a retelling of opera (&lt;em&gt;Carmen&lt;/em&gt;), and a modern pastiche of drama (&lt;em&gt;Romeo and Juliet&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Juliet’s use of comic pastiche rather than tragedy&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mock transformations of modern London into an epic plane&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Juliet’s “style”: navigating the  “isms” of 19th century through language
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Use of arch, humorous style as social commentary
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Juliet dialogically incorporates and ironizes Marxist and Darwinian language: “it was a struggle of self vs. environment. I am unit of the proletariat” (35).&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;the “aforesaids” and “Whereas’s”of the law office are mockingly incorpated into her resignation letter,  ads: “Shorthand and Typewriter (female)”&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Questions of the ambiguity of class of type-writer girl played out in the many different registers of titles for her position: “type-writer girl”, “Lady Type-Writer,” “horrid paragraphist,” “that sort of person,”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Language of ads, language of the legal office, Juliet’s “epic” pastiche style&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Type-writer girls,” class ambiguity, and class feeling
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Juliet is miss classed first by the anarchists, then by Mr. Blank&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Juliet’s ability to recognize characters’ class by their fabrics: cotton-wool, black satin&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Comic with class signifiers: “I have large estates at Herfordshire…”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“Amateur” vs. “Professional” writing&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Class ambiguity plays out in space.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Juliet’s drawing room is the National Art Gallery&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Questions of class relations complicate gendered spaces: Juliet, because of class is closer to Mr. Blank.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Invention of Bohemia: Juliet as educated urban proletariat woman&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Meta”-textuality and Juliet’s extradiegetic comments
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Self conscious narration: reflecting on the story’s lack of love interest (73), on her omissions, on her “failed” epic style&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Structurally, labor is at the center at the center of the novel
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The center of the story is on the anarchist camp and the Nicholas icon: labor, capital, ideology (it is only after that that the “This story is deficient in a love interest” line is introduced 73)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The ending declaration: I am the type-writer girl = both admission of the cheap romantic tie up to the ordeal AND to her socio-economic situation that forces her to live off writing and selling fiction.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Race and national identity
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Léon (Caliban) and racial anxiety&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mr. Blank’s Oriental decor&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Juliet’s own ambiguous parentage: Gypsy “on my mother’s Lowland Scot or Anglo-Indian” (117); “gypsy or American or Anglo-Indian”(136)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;passages-of-note&quot;&gt;Passages of Note&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I have know knack of pathos; even at difficult turns I am apt to see rather the humorous than the tragic side of things” (99)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“My life at Romeo’s was a life of routine… All our history is episode, with blanks between, which just serve conveniently to divide the chapters” (85)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Woman and machines
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“A type-writer I was and a type-writer I must remain” (28)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“I am a woman first, and a cyclist after”(62)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Sierra Eckert</name><email>sierra.c.eckert@gmail.com</email></author><category term="class" /><category term="communication technologies" /><category term="gender" /><category term="race" /><summary>*The Type-Writer Girl*, Grant Allan (1897)</summary></entry></feed>
